This video demonstrates how to assess near-vision and dispense glasses.
Wash your hands and don PPE.
You will need near-vision chart, pen and clinical notes, range of reading glasses and a 40cm long piece of string.
Explain what you're going to do in-game consent.
Sit the patient comfortably in a well-lit place.
Use a string to make sure the chart is held at the correct 40cm distance.
Ask them to read down the chart with both eyes together.
smallest line they can read comfortably.
If they cannot read the N8 line then try with
plus 1.5 diopter sphere glasses.
If they still cannot read N8 then use the next higher power
and so on until they can comfortably read N8 text.
Make sure the glasses fit ok and the
patient is happy with their appearance.